#### **NKOSINGIPHILE DLAMINI**

### **PERSONAL DETAILS**

Name(s) : Nkosingiphile Malangeni

Surname : Dlamini

Date of Birth : 19 April 1994 Place of Birth : Sigombeni

Gender : Male
Nationality : Swazi
Marital Status : Single
Religion : Christianity

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

Cell phone Number : +268 7668 5765

Postal Address : P O Box 1096 Matsapha, Swaziland

Physical Address : Manzini, Mbekelweni, Sigombeni, Lomngeletjane

Email address : mphilemdlamini@gmail.com

Alternative contact : +268 7668 2628

#### **SUMMARY**

IT support with over 3 years' experience in IT industry at Computronics Systems Pty Ltd and Eswatini Mobile to name a few. I have enhanced my skills in customer service level support with regards to local companies, individual customers and retail industry giants. My greatest strength is business awareness, forward thinking and sustainable development.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

2022-04-> Current

# **Remote Support and Data Clerk**

Weownomy Global

- > Data entry for members in Excel
- > Shares calculations data analysis
- Formula creations simplicity for members in Excel Sheets
- > Document creation and management
- > Applications Support

## 2021-06->2021-07 Surveyor (Nkomiyahlaba Constituency)

Emlalatini Development Centre

- Nkomiyahlaba Constituency surveys
- Responsible for accurately entering data for all areas of online learning survey
- ➤ Entering student data for MTN mobile radio, SBS1 radio lessons, Eswatini Times lessons for survey purposes
- > Analysing and cleansing of existing data sets
- Coding, compiling, retrieving data for survey web application reporting purposes

## 2019-01->2019-07 Infrastructure Engineer

Computronics Systems Pty Ltd

- Prepared infrastructure performance analyses and preventive maintenance reports.
- Monitored and report network performance issues to Technical management.
- Administered user accounts and passwords in Active Directory, shared folders.
- Administered network printers create and modify user accounts and usage
- Provided IT expertise and recommendations to other departments on procurement of IT related products.
- Provided specific training to users when required for new systems rollouts and enhancements.
- > Ensuring work is extensively done in accordance to scope and completed within SLA.

# **2018-09->2018-12 Customer Service Agent**

Eswatini Mobile Ltd

- > Field work service and fixed wireless support with customer surveys around Matsapha district
- Activating, registering new and existing sim cards on VELA and setting up E-Mali (mobile money platform)
- Providing post-sales support to acquired customers
- Ensuring that targets are met by upselling and crossselling
- > Advertising new products and services
- Documenting customer data and uploading for administration application support.

#### 2017 -01 -> 2018-09 IT Technician

Computronics Systems Pty LTD

- Providing first line support on all incident logged and assigned to local IT helpdesk.
- Optimized IT workload through designing a web application to balance engineer tasks.
- ➤ Installation, configuration, maintaining and troubleshooting network devices-servers, network points and network printers, switches, routers, access points.
- Ensured all workstations are working efficient and running updated, latest and licensed antivirus definitions and windows patches.
- Managed local and onsite helpdesk support and recording requests submitted by users, either in person, email or telephonically.
- Ensure IT compliance during audits facilitate IT related process to comply with internal and external audits
- Implemented site maintenance levels and data capturing for software and hardware statistics.
- Provide IT related support to technical issues, assist in maintenance and troubleshooting of IT related equipment from laptops, PCs, printers, mobile phones, PI resolution issues, as well as projects that required IT input.

#### **PROJECT EXPERIENCE**

- Baylor project-Network Planning, assessment, setup and termination of Network points, patching of wall boxes and mounting cabinets. Clinics networked include: Ekufiken Clinic, Mbabane Health Center, Tambuti Clinic, Big Bend Correctional and many more.
- Eswatini Mobile field work: customer surveys, android mobile support, email, internet service, data collection on queries and suggestions, customer registrations, promotions and upgrades
- Emlalatini Development Centre online learning surveys, working on remote constituencies with their local primary and high schools. Teaching communities about online learning opportunities including royal kraals.

## **SOFTWARE**

- Advanced skills in Microsoft windows 7, 8, 10 and Windows Server 2012 R2
- Microsoft Office Suite skills(word, excel, power point, outlook, Access, publisher, project)
- Computer languages: Java, C#, C++, PHP, ASP.NET, HTML, CSS and MySQL
- **Programming Platforms:** WordPress, NetBeans, Visual Studio, XAMP and Bootstrap Studio.

#### **PROFESSIONAL SKILLS**

- Client Relationship Management
- Excellent customer service skills
- Teamwork collaboration skills
- Innovative and organizational awareness
- Extensive clinical diagnosis in software and hardware

#### **EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND**

| 2014-09-><br>2017-10 | Limkokwing University of Creative Technology Associate Degree in Information Technology |
|----------------------|---|
|                      |   |
| 2011-12              | Certificate in Microsoft Office Excel   |
| 2007-01->            | Ekukhanyeni High School   |
| 2011-12              | Swaziland General Certificate of Secondary Education                                    |

## **TRAININGS ATTENDED**

- > SQL Fundamentals Course
- ➤ Microsoft Windows Server 2012 R2
- CompTIA A+
- CompTIA Network +
- Cisco Networking
- Social Media Marketing

#### **LANGUAGES**

Linguistic: fluently in English and SiSwati

**Hobbies:** Table tennis and chess

#### **ACTIVITIES AND INTEREST**

I am interested in a position that will utilize my skills in information technology environment: IT systems, web applications, networking, database systems, server technologies, cloud services, website design and helpdesk tasks to elevate my experience and innovation techniques. Additionally, I am self-motivated and capable to learn new technologies and solutions

# **REFERENCES**

1. Mr. Nkosinathi Dlamini Computronics Systems (PTY) LTD

Cell: (+268) 76053646

Email: nathi@computronics.sz

2. Mr. Maseko

Emlalatini Development Centre

Cell: 78513034

Email: <a href="mailto:simon323maseko@gmail.com">simon323maseko@gmail.com</a>

3. Mr. Lwazi Ciniso Dlamini

SinaweTech Ltd Cell: 79576338

Email: <a href="mailto:dlaminilwaziciniso@gmail.com">dlaminilwaziciniso@gmail.com</a>

Web: electronsz.github.io

4. Mr. Yusuf Shabangu

Limkokwing University of Creative Technology

Tel: (+268) 2422 0532 Cell: (+268) 76363660

Email: yusof.shabanqu@limkokwing.ac.sz